

💌 carloshvronchi@gmail.com | 😭 chronchi.github.io | 🖸 chronchi | 🛅 chronchi | 💆 chronchi

Summary.

Mathematician doing a PhD in molecular life sciences in a breast cancer lab at the Federal Polytechnic School of Lausanne (EPFL) in Switzerland. Developed statistical algorithms for biomarker discovery with transcriptomics data in breast cancer. Experienced in transcriptomic analysis, including single cell and bulk RNA-seq and microarray. I am dedicated and detail oriented, using recent tools for reports and pipelines using reproducible standards, such as quarto markdown, docker and shiny apps. Developed novel biostatistical algorithms and pipelines to analyse growth measurement data from in vivo and high-throughput experiments using bayesian inference. Experienced in communicating with bioscientists regarding their projects and helping them tackling their questions. Previously worked with deep learning and artificial intelligence in problems related to protein stability and computer vision.

Education

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne - EPFL

Lausanne, VD, Switzerland

Sep. 2020 - August 2024

PHD IN MOLECULAR LIFE SCIENCES

· Supervisor: Cathrin Brisken

• Fellow of Marie Curie actions (MSCA) - Horizon 2020

University of São Paulo - USP

São Carlos, SP, Brazil

Aug. 2017 - Nov. 2019

M.Sc. in Mathematics

• Supervisor: Marcio Gameiro; FAPESP fellow; GPA: 3.8/4.0

Rutgers University Piscataway, New Jersey, USA

VISITING RESEARCH STUDENT

Jan. 2019 - Jun. 2019

• Supervisor: Konstantin Mischaikow; BEPE FAPESP Excellence Scholarship

Federal University of Paraná - UFPR

Curitiba, PR, Brazil

B.Sc. IN MATHEMATICS

Apr. 2013 - Jul. 2017

- · Awarded an excellence scholarship to spend 1.5 years in Germany. One year spent at RFW-Universität Bonn, Germany
- GPA: 4/4

Research Experience _____

PhD student at EPFL Lausanne, Switzerland

MARIE CURIE FELLOW (MSCA - HORIZON 2020)

Sep. 2020 - Current

- Developed a novel platform (EMBER) for biomarker discovery and breast cancer diagnosis using bulk RNA-seq and microarray. Manuscript under review
- · Developed several R packages for biostatistics and bioinformatic analysis in the lab (biogrowleR), increasing the productivity of team members and standardizing several statistical protocols. Manuscript in preparation
- · Used Bayesian Inference in novel ways to extract insights from data generated in the lab, leading to better interpretation of the results
- · Developed several analysis pipelines for transcriptomics data that is shared in the group and used by non-bioinformaticians as well
- · Experienced in communicating with bioscientists. Paying attention to their needs and helping them in clarifying their questions with biostatistics and computational biology
- · Supervised and mentored master students in individual projects
- Went to multiple conferences in different countries to present my research
- · Lead teaching assistant of genomics and bioinformatics in 2022 and 2023, a class with over 100 students. Organized exercise sessions, R tutorials and tutored several students in individual projects
- Started and organized bi-weekly seminar with experts on cancer prevention

Research intern at AstraZeneca

Cambridge, UK

Oct. 2022 - Dec. 2022

FUNDED BY MSCA - HORIZON 2020

- Worked in a project to extract insights in real-world data
- · Presented my research for multiple scientists in both the bioscience and bioinformatics department
- · Introduced novel ways to interpret their drug pipeline discovery platform results by using bayesian inference

Research assistant at Brisken's lab at School of Life Sciences - EPFL

Lausanne, Switzerland Jan. 2020 - August 2020

funded by École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL)

Improved current packaging standards in the laboratory and introduced software best practices (ttmap)

Master's student São Carlos, Brazil

FUNDED BY FAPESP Aug. 2017 - Nov. 2020

- Developed novel ways to predict protein stability by applying persistent homology, tools from topological data analysis (TDA) and deep learning
- · Combined machine learning and persistent homology to improve the accuracy in image classification problems
- Implemented TDA algorihtms in Julia (MapperMDS.jl, PersistenceImage.jl), allowing researchers to speed up their computations by using a faster language
- Developed web-based tools to visualize the results of optimal cycle extraction from persistent homology, helping researchers understand their results (3dPD)
- · Collaboration with material science researchers to understand the optimal Hansen Solubility Parameters of organic semiconductors (HSP.jl)
- Awarded the best poster presentation among all master students in the mathematics department at ICMC USP 2018

Undergradute researcher

Curitiba, Brazil

funded by Programa de Atração de Jovens Talentos (CSF-PAJT)

Jul. 2016 - Jul. 2017

Applied Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) to predict LaTeX characters, improving the accuracy of existing algorithms

IT and Data Science

Programming languges

—

- R, python, Julia
- · bash, docker, Slurm
- LaTeX

ember

HTTPS://CHRONCHI.GITHUB.IO/EMBER/

• Novel breast cancer diagnosis tool for biomarker discovery and treatment decision

biogrowleR

HTTPS://UPBRI.GITLAB.IO/BIOGROWLER/

• Tutorial, pipelines and randomization algorithms for longitudinal in vivo and and in vitro experiments in R

ttmap

HTTPS://GITLAB.COM/UPBRI/TTMAP

• Implementation of Two-Tier Mapper in R, a topological tool to analyse RNA-Seq data

ProteinPersistent.jl

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/CHRONCHI/PROTEINPERSISTENT.JL

· Julia package that provides functions to obtain the persistent homology of a protein using the python package ripser

Languages_

Portuguese (Native), English (excellent command/C1), German (good command/B2), French (good command/B2)

Hobbies

- · Table tennis: captain of my team in the Swiss inter-cantonal championship
- · Soccer
- ·Hiking